netratings.com 2005-12-30

# Nielsen//NetRatings: A global leader in Internet media and market research

**Nielsen//NetRatings’ Privacy Policy**

**Privacy Notice**  
Nielsen//NetRatings (“NetRatings”) is committed to the privacy of all visitors to its Web site (www.nielsen-netratings.com). To that end, NetRatings has established this Privacy Policy (“Policy”) to protect each visitor’s privacy. The Policy explains what and how NetRatings collects, uses, stores and protects the information gathered from its Web site. _To read our privacy policy regarding the information we collect on behalf of our clients on their Web sites through our SiteCensus, AdIntelligence and Market Intelligence services, please **click here**._ By using and visiting the Web site, you agree to this Policy and the uses made of personal information as set forth herein or amended hereafter. 

**What Information is Collected and How It’s Used**  
Upon visiting the Web site, your browser automatically sends NetRatings your IP  
address, the type of browser you are using and certain other information. NetRatings may use this information for research and marketing purposes and to enhance the Web site.

When individuals subscribe to our newsletter or request other information from  
NetRatings, personal information, including first and last name, job title, company name, e-mail address, business address and telephone number and the industry in which your company operates, may be requested. You are not required to provide NetRatings with this personal information; however, the newsletter and other requested information cannot be sent to you without it.

Personal information is also collected from Nielsen//NetRatings’ clients who login and provide a password. Such access to the Nielsen//NetRatings’ services and Web site may also be governed by the agreement between your employer and NetRatings. NetRatings may monitor and record such activity in order to verify compliance with that agreement and to track your activity on the Web site including, the reports and data accessed and downloaded and the time spent on each section or report contained in the service. This activity may be shared with NetRatings’ affiliates and certain third parties as provided in this Policy.

There may be features on the Web site allowing you to contact NetRatings via e-mail, which provides NetRatings with your e-mail address and certain other personal information contained in the e-mail. By sending NetRatings e-mail, you demonstrate your consent to knowingly and voluntarily provide us with personal information.

NetRatings will not sell, trade, or otherwise disclose personally identifiable information to any third party, unless stated otherwise in this Policy, required by law, or as required to protect NetRatings’ rights. NetRatings may disclose information collected from the Web site to its agents, contractors and other third parties as may be necessary to perform certain functions on behalf of NetRatings. However, they are prohibited from using the information collected on the Web site for any other purpose. If NetRatings is sold in whole or in part, various forms of the personal information discussed in this Policy may be included in the assets transferred to a third party.

**Children’s Privacy**  
We intend the Web site to be used only by adults. Children are to obtain their parents’ permission prior to sending any personal information to us over the Internet. The Web site does not knowingly or intentionally collect information on children under the age of 13. If we discover that a child under the age of 13 has supplied personal information to NetRatings via the Web site without their parent’s consent, that information will be deleted from our system.

**Use of Cookies**  
Cookies are only used when existing Nielsen//NetRatings’ clients visit the Web site, and not when other individuals visit the Web site, subscribe to the newsletter, or request other information from NetRatings. Cookies are small pieces of information transferred to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser to enable NetRatings’ systems to recognize your preferences and settings. Cookies collect information such as the type of search engine used, the sections of the website visited and other website usage information. NetRatings may use this information for research purposes and to enhance the Web site. The information is aggregated prior to such use and does not include any  
personally identifiable information.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies and you may manually disable them. For more information on disabling cookies, go to the “help” menu on your browser. Additional information on cookies can be obtained from the Federal Trade Commission website at www.ftc.gov. The Web site may still be viewed after disabling cookies.

**Accessing and Changing Your Personal Information**  
You may unsubscribe to the newsletter by clicking the “Newsletter” icon at www.nielsen-netratings.com and following the prompts. You may also send e-mail to [webmaster@netratings.com](mailto:webmaster@netratings.com?subject=Please%20change%20my%20information%20in%20your%20database) requesting access and changes to your personal information. For your protection, NetRatings will take the necessary precautions to verify your identity prior to changing or allowing access to your personal information.

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**  
NetRatings may change and update this Privacy Policy, including materially changing the use made of personal information described herein. Any change or update to our privacy policy will be posted on our Web site under “Privacy Policy” at least 30 days prior to their implementation. Your continued use of the Web site after the effective date of any changes will constitute your acceptance of all of the changes.

**Questions**  
We welcome comments and suggestions regarding the NetRatings’ privacy notice. Please send questions about our privacy policy or the information we have collected from you to privacy@netratings.com. If you believe your personal information has been misused or handled in such a manner contrary to the policy stated above, please contact us at [privacy@netratings.com](mailto:privacy@netratings.com?subject=Privacy%20question%20submitted%20via%20the%20website).

**Miscellaneous**  
This Policy and any issue or dispute regarding privacy concerns will be governed by and interpreted in accordance with the laws of the State of New York and the United States of America, without regard to the choice of law provisions. This Policy and the Terms of Use are the entire agreement between the parties relating to use of the Web site and person information collected by NetRatings. All references in this Policy to “NetRatings” and “Nielsen//NetRatings” shall mean NetRatings, Inc.

Updated February 5, 2003
